hello and welcome to the junkyard love
[Music]
podcast well uh I kind of interrupted
You by hitting recording my apologies
there man but um you're kind of just in
a process of telling me about how like
having having a kid just like changed
your relationship with God is kind of
like what what we're talking about it it
changed it changed everything bro like I
said I just I just I'm I'm there for the
burst like I'm very like I'm I'm right
I'm right in the mix bro like I'm right
there
like I haven't pulled one out yet but
ideally that would be the plan um at
some point but yeah I
just I just don't see how you can
receive again a child and just not
believe that this that this is magical
and this comes straight from Source like
even just on the craziest level of just
biology like how is it that we're
created so perfectly right and so you
know I gave and you know this is so
different I feel like just even from you
and me catching up um from even the pods
we've done before if anybody ever you
know has seen that or know me but you
know nobody really knows the side of me
and that's why I've kind of Taken like a
little break from social media and
posting and and being out you know in
the mix and being outside as I like to
call it because I'm trying to find my
footing in this whole new life that I
live and you know what is it like I know
that it's super important
to men especially to like represent
something like it's it's very important
it's very a part of like the masculine
being to be like all right I represent
this like I'm going to take it you know
I'm taking it across the Finish Line
right I'm taking them I'm carrying the
burning torch and and here we go it's
super important and and um I feel like
you know I had that before with the bike
was a very false sense of self
accomplishment right and I have um a
great relationship with like the man
that I used to be and as far as like I
was so close to being the right
man yet just just change directions a
little bit right so it's
like um and again you know all kind of
like what we were touching on before and
I I don't know if we just want to keep
going or what but
um the
man just everything I I just gave myself
credit for everything and and and I just
felt so fraudulent about that I really
did like I now I look
back I even believe that the bike was
from God I really do CU it's like at
that
moment in that point in my life I was
going to commit
suicide so all of a sudden this thing
shows up and I'm so invested in it and I
love it so much it just keeps me around
like
I don't know bro I just have a hard time
wrestling with that idea that that I I
just don't believe in coincidence right
do you do you see like I think about it
with myself too like as much as I know
now that like wow I'm so glad that those
things didn't become my longterm I know
that I was exposed to and opened up to
much more broad things than what I
thought I was meant for at that time or
whatever do you see it as do you see it
as a very part of who you are today
though like do you for me it's hard as
much as I want to have this magic thing
in my head like oh if I could rewind
time and not do that I wouldn't I'm not
like that at all I see that like I had
to go through those things and those
were clearly the lessons that I needed
to get to this version of myself do you
you feel no I 100% one I I think that I
think men for and this is you know I try
to stick on certain thing like I feel
like people in general like we can go a
little but I think men specifically um
only because that's what I'm
experiencing right is we find our
spirituality climbing the mountain right
I always have this like funny joke with
my wife is just like you know she can
come out of the bedroom after reading
scripture and she's just balling her
eyes out and it's just so magical and
all this kind of stuff and I'm just like
I don't experience that when I read the
book like I just don't you know what I
mean but like when it snows and it's 25
and I'm in the river I'm I'm like oh
here he is bro like oh my gosh like I
feel you like and it's just like I'm as
far as just like you know rewinding a
little bit with the bike like I said I
always have just given myself credit and
I've just always felt this sense of
like you're kind of not a fraud like I'm
like I am who I say am I know I show up
like there's no nobody that can look at
me and say you're not doing what you say
you do like there's there's no part
about that everything was always like
out there like you know you say you put
in this kind of work and you say you do
this and you say you do that and there
you are you know let me pause
that and you know that was never that
was never a question but the question
was like why do this thing happen you
know and like I said
I Jake and you know High sight's always
2020 right so you know looking back like
I'm like that came to me that kept me
alive and I feel like that was the gift
it was like oh my gosh bro like you
really are serious about this like
you're really thinking about that you're
really thinking about taking your life
like let me give you let me give you a
distraction for a few years and then
you'll figure it out and that's what it
was like you know my wife jokes
now um I mean I drink an ungodly amount
of caffeine bro like ungodly amount and
she's just like why is this necessary
and I just thought I thought I thought
I'm like cuz it's the only thing that I
know is not the best for me that I don't
kick you know what I mean because I'm
like uh I'm mad disciplined with the
food and all these other things in the
gym and all this stuff and I'm just like
I know it's not the best and I'm just
like I
found peace in chaos so that heart
pumping adrenaline thing that I feel at
home home yeah you've worked there you
spent a lot hours in that spot not only
did I spent a lot of hours there but I I
spent peace there right so it's like
this Comfort within this
like chaos of just adrenaline and all
these things that was like so attached
to the bike that it created such a great
relationship too and also too you know
the bike was the ability for me to have
an out that wasn't my fault that never
happened right so perfect I'll just go
as hard as I can on this thing this
thing will take me out it's not even my
fault and it just never happened not
only did it never happen I have video
proof that I can send you that you can
pop in here of somehow this guy's
rolling around on the freeway he rolls
twice and he's lands on his feet
multiple times right or a bike runs into
a bus station and somehow I just fall
off at the last second and land on my
feet like it
just like I said bro I just look back
and I'm just like something had its hand
on me you know what I mean and I just I
have a hard time not going or saying
like that was all me yeah like give me
the credit here I'm the guy you know um
so I wrestled with that for a while and
that's why like I said I feel like
there's a lot of what I was a few years
ago is just not there anymore you know
yeah yeah I mean I I think a lot about
like I've been doing this podcast this
because I started it pre pandemic so
it's been like it's been a little little
over five years and um I mean you were
like you were amongst my first 50 and
you you came on multiple times you were
reoccurring so like we're in a weird way
we were going through a lot of similar
stuff together um and it's interesting
though because like I and I actually I
was typing a wall of text to you when we
were texting just like last week or
whatever and I didn't hit s because it
just kept going on I feel like this is
something that could just continuously
it's hard to it's hard to land on what
exactly am I trying to say but uh there
is
like I I have I don't want to listen
back to those episodes um I'm not
ashamed of those episodes but it's
almost an unrecognizable version of me
like it's it's almost like in a lot of
ways dude what's for me is like I I was
going through a lot of like deeply
spiritual trauma stuff as well like I
was going through basically a spiritual
psychosis and I just put a mic in front
of me and had my friends come over you
know and so like it's beautiful it's
beautiful um so so all that to say as
much as there's like oh man I don't
really like if you pulled a clip up from
that time and said like hey what do you
think about this I'm probably G to have
a different input now but I also see the
way that if I hadn't done those things
and been so vulnerable myself I wouldn't
be where I'm at with this podcast where
people are comfortable now to be like
completely vulnerable uh open it's
created a space like without me even
trying I've created like uh this space
for other people to come and just
completely like L lay it down and be
authentic I don't know in the podcast
space
it I don't know it could get cheesy
quick and it could feel like people are
trying to sell you stuff but you know
I'm 111 episodes in and I've you know
it's all it's all been free I've never
tried to sell anybody anything it's just
been yeah facts here's and the people
around me and the people that I'm
meeting and like what we're going
through and hopefully it helps you know
facts yeah I like that yeah um well so I
I I thought about what's useful to
people because I'm sure there's a good
handful of people who have listened to
the other episodes and and that's
awesome but uh as far as let's like
rewind a little bit people who have just
clicked on it we were just cing bro and
we were just jumped right in yeah yeah
yeah well so so let's let's set a stage
and bring in some newcomers like hey you
know wave to all of our friends I'm sure
we have plenty of Pacific Northwest
people who know both of us hello but
you're going to hear some repeats from
us for a few minutes anyway so AB
welcome to the podcast brother
appreciate you bro yeah I'm excited to
be here I'm excited to run it back this
will be I think this will be the fourth
time bro we did one we did two two Doo
and then we did one with my guy Matt
remember yeah that was amazing yes this
would be the fourth time that was a
blast well anybody can go check those I
mean there certainly like we've grown as
men and and it's been a while but those
there's some good valuable valuable
stuff in those older episodes so I uh
Nate man will you give me just like kind
of a a bio I know it's an impossible
question but will you fill us in if we
don't know who you
are yeah uh wow and it's funny because
we were just talking right before we
turned the camera on or where if this is
going to start about how um I'm in a
phase where I'm trying to find my
footing right I identified with one
thing um which was stunt writing for a
very long time um I spent 10 years of my
life dedicating my entire life all all
all my time all my money all my energy
to one thing that
um I feel like it's just now a piece of
me and not the whole bit of me so you
know to give a bio man I I'm working on
that right I'm working on a new one um
I'm I'm a I'm a new dad um three kids uh
under four years um husband married
working on that that's my main focus is
my family and my marriage right now um
the last time we spoke um man I was
managing a restaurant um fully full
entrepreneur um run a Content agency
fantastic um
been the thing that I needed I feel like
to pull to to pull the dog back back out
of me from like kind of getting out of
the bike and into something new is just
like you know put your back up against
the wall and have moues de feed and not
know where the next check's coming from
you know um I feel like these are the
type of moments that I needed to
actually find which is kind of what we
were talking about before was of my
spirituality because I just kept leaning
on myself right like you know believe in
yourself like do do this yourself
yourself yourself yourself yourself and
I feel like that is so the narrative
of self-help social media like you know
all this like motivational Guru stuff
which I used to be that guy like I that
was my Mo was like yo I did this like
you know you know and I just found I
always found that and we know this right
we've had even this conversation you
know years past that the finish line is
always like after you like break the
tape and you get that
ah it's
empty right so it's like what if I know
this right and I'm fortunate Jake and I
think this is something where I feel
like I'm going to be a testimony towards
is I reached a place previously like we
have this conversation where 99.9% of
people ever get in their life and that's
will you find something in this life
that you're willing to die for and not
only are you willing to die for it but
willingly die for for it right I mean I
used to tell my mom Mom I love you if I
pull out this driveway and I don't come
home don't be sad why because I wanted
to be doing this this is what this is
how I wanted to go okay what that means
is death or the thought of death is
where you really come
alive this is like and honestly what I
didn't even know and I was thinking
about this the other day and wow when we
were going to pod is and I didn't think
of this until I was running a mile in
20° weather like we were just talking
about before is think the thought of
death and being okay with death is true
Faith think about
that like you cannot be willing to go
out like me and jump over the handlebars
on the highway going 70 miles an hour if
you don't believe that something's there
to cover
you what do you think people what do you
think other people think of death why is
it I I think that people are often
fearful of death and we avoid the very
thought of it even though it's one it's
even though it's actually one of the
only promises that there is here think
about it what's like we're always that's
what we're always Jake you know this
right we had these conversations
everybody wants like the guarantee and
the comfort and and the the routine and
all this kind of stuff guess what the
only actual promise here is that you're
going to you're going
out so the fact that we're afraid of the
only actual promise actually stops is
from The Full Experience
here right and again so kind of what I
was saying before is I actually went
through this phase when I was like first
Awakening right and first having kids
like okay well the man before which we
had spoke about the liar the cheater the
deceiver the you know the breaking the
law running from the cops doing all this
doing all that causing trouble for no
good reason at all he has to die
and it's only true to some extent right
it's not he has to die it's what can how
do you evolve him right it's like I look
at it like a sculpture right like okay
this sculpture looks good but how can we
make this you know for lack a better
term like Greek god can we chisel him
more right like I just I need more in
the obliques bro you know what I mean
like I need a little more the shoulders
are kind of lacking you know what I mean
it's the same sculpture right but it's
more chisel it's more developed I think
is a great word so I went through this
phase
where man this is just you know
scripture says boast in your weaknesses
um I was kind of docile because I'm like
okay he's dead Nasty Nate is dead okay
now
what who okay so okay how does how do I
navigate this right and it's like no he
doesn't die he he he evolves what was
the word I just used he uh he develops
okay so the same thing and I man I wrote
this caption the other day bro and this
perfectly describes what do they say
about Simplicity right
um as Simplicity being the most powerful
thing I wrote this caption and I could
send it to Jake and this is something I
said for my son's birthday and I tried
and I just wrote out paragraphs and
paragraphs and paragraphs and I was like
okay how can you get this into a couple
sentences right
any parents out there the first thing
being a a father right would I want my
son to be proud to model me as a man
right and would I want my daughter to
marry a man like me if you need to ask
any other questions I don't then you are
you are lost right right think about it
if my daughter brought me through the
door am I going to be like oh God like
we have an issue or am I going to be
like he's going to take care of her
right
man
um and my son right like man is he gonna
go God you know when he's old like this
is what my dad did right and how do how
do we get to the point where we're so
deep in that sort of servitude that you
understand that self-development is how
you do that right so this is how you
incorporate self into it is because if I
don't go if I don't go kill the dragons
when he's out in
War what advice do I have to give right
so I try to tell myself those three
things my daughter my son and then also
the last thing how do you get through
hard situations and this is for parents
live the advice you want to give them
right so I'm going to go to Jet when he
say
and tell them to nut up like when I'm
sitting in the garage which is where I
sit when I'm like how is this going to
work like how are we going to get out of
this like
right nut up like this is it this is a
perfect opportunity for you to say one
day God I remember
when and this is what I okay and this is
what I I I said this caption I feel like
this perfectly kind of um describes what
I'm saying the only thing I truly care
about is that when you grow up and you
have your own kids that you think I was
a man worth modeling that you and your
you that you your siblings and your mom
know that I gave everything I had in me
and every day would be a perfect day to
die for you and man that's just it bro
like that's nasty Nate but he's
developed right like I bro when I tell
you that I would have just had a smile
on my face to die on the bike and and
know that like the following weekend
that my boys were going to go run from
the cops because I had passed the
weekend before I would have been so
happy and I was just willing to lay down
my life for that that season of my life
and it's like if I don't keep that I'm
I'm missing the point of why that
happened right so it's like I when
people talk about trauma right or like
and I just I want to be careful with
that because I I I I want to previous
podcast and I I think it would be
fantastic to watch these old podcasts
that we did to see how far we've come
right and to see me talk about trauma
and all this and all and this just so
new age and again I I'm here to you know
there's aund other 111 episodes if I
piss you off you can watch another one
right but my the what the rule book that
I believe in that has saved me from the
depth of Hell tells me that this is
black and white and this is how this
thing goes okay and
I just believe that there's so much
depth here that we miss right as far as
like the test is supposed to be the
testimony right so it's like I feel like
we sh we we blame the trauma and like
the thing so much that you fail to go
wow and again here goes the
representation Jake that I was talking
about a team to
represent I that happened to me so I fix
it so it doesn't happen to
others what other cause do you need to
fight for right and now we're talking
about um men's mental health right and
again we have talked about this in
previous episodes where I would be
embarrassed for somebody to watch that
not understanding that happiness is not
the aim fulfillment is the aim what does
fulfillment mean this is worth it okay
am I happy all the time raising my three
children uh homeschooling them doing all
the hard stuff no I'm absolutely not
happy but then when I watch my son
operate in a public setting and kids are
doing stuff and he's doing something
else I sure am like wow this is worth it
bro you can't buy that dude you you
can't like pay pay subscription price
for that feeling that's not you know
falling in love and working hard for
something you're proud of has nothing to
do with busting a nut dude it's like
get caught up trying to like thinking
that if I'm just happy if I just really
get what I think I want then I'll be
fulfilled and then what about tomorrow
dude you know yeah sorry W gone no and I
love that you said that so again the
idea is
like um you know and this is so and I've
done so much work on what are the parts
of you know the four year what are the
parts of the four-year-old podcast that
or the 5-year-old podcast that are
valuable right that need to go okay you
need to work on the things that he was
talking about so whatever five years ago
that podcast that we were talking about
there's the battles and there's the boys
that are now your audience right that
need this that need this that need this
wisdom you know what I'm saying so um
yeah I just you know and you know
jumping off from there just what we
talked about before in the last episode
just like you know always trying to like
you know seek this like happiness and
you know uh you know everything are so
hard it's like yeah that's how it is and
that's how it's supposed to be right my
favorite scripture to whom much is given
much will be required which is
Spider-Man great power great
responsibility right if you want what
you say you want expect it to be
difficult right but again scripture bro
I mean this book there is I'm as I'm
sitting with it right here there's
nothing there's nothing wrong in here
right so um that's where wisdom is
created is in difficulty right and we
know this but this is like all these
things and even Jake us going back to
the people that we were talking about
before Bob Proctor you know Neville
Godard all these people guess what these
guys were quoting scripture bro these
guys were quoting scripture um who who's
the super super old Neville Goddard and
um
bro they were quoting they were quoting
scripture I didn't realize that until I
was was like listening to them right
thinking like oh these guys are the
these are the guys like right because
like oh I'm not listening to the the new
guys I'm listening to the OG's and I'm
like but they were listening to the OG's
which is the disciples right um even um
Napoleon Hill and he was quoting
scripture I'm like bro these guys that
we believe are like the these are the O
and then the people that are ripping
their material right because we're all
nothing is created nor destroyed right
we can all agree with that all these
ideas are already floating it's our life
experience that brings out the New
Perspective which Now new ears can hear
new ears can hear yeah but the thing is
we would have never
accessed the
scripture in the way that you read it
now you wouldn't have had access to it
meaning much to you if it was was
inputed to if it was handed in the same
way it is to you now meaning um the way
that those people that we learned from
the way that they heard it and
interpreted it and ran it through their
own experiences and their own experience
of being a man and gave it to us that
was enough for us to go that's
interesting I like that and then sure
enough five six years later you're like
oh I'm like jumping ahead to I'm reading
the books that he read uh and then I'm
finding out who the author that is and
reading that book yeah yeah so it's so
that that metaphor right there is
exactly what I believe that it is to
be men and to be and to go again there's
another scripture um it doesn't re it
doesn't relate to death but it's the um
the servant of the
talents um guys are asked to hold hold
money you know gold whatever they're
asked to invest it and then when they
bring back more the the you know the
king says I'm well done my good and
faithful servant and I just see that as
such a great and this has again nothing
to do with death but such a great thing
to hear before your time here is is is
gone right like well done my good and
faithful servant like you know you you
have you have I have entrusted you with
little therefore I will give you much is
is what it says but it's like I feel
it's like I've trusted you with with
what you were supposed to do here right
and it's like that's I feel like like
you said we wouldn't have heard it if it
wasn't from there was like this line
like don't be the guy in this life in
your lineage in in in like in your town
in your sphere in your purpose don't be
the guy that gets out of line right that
you're asking to sign yourself up for
misery and a life of just like chasing
pleasure and all this kind of things
when you exit I call it like um I love
using War
as metaphor because it's so barbaric
right like imagine you have a post to
sit at right this is your post here's
your gun here's your thing and this is
your no one else can sit here this is
I'm supposed to guard this door this is
this is my shift and no one else is
coming imagine you get up right like
that's how I look at it with purpose and
what we're supposed to do here is like
like you said you know you were
um we can be the next guy in the line
that find the information that saved us
from you know kind of both where we were
we're like bro I just want to cash this
in like I kind of just wanted to be done
here but guess what Jake I realize it's
all been the same mentality bro this is
how close anybody that's in misery you
are so close to being right where you're
supposed to be because the mentality
never changed I would rather do this
than be here okay
I take that same thing and I just Jake I
remember this bro I remember being like
bro just just do it bro just do it
because I would say I would rather die
than experience what I'm experiencing
right now and I say the same thing all
the
time if I don't squeeze the juice out of
me right the potential that I feel like
I'm that is
there I'd rather just cash it in and I
know that I won't cash it in so with
that being said anything short of
squeezing a
juice is like death so that's what gives
me the gust though is like this is life
for death and how did I come about this
scripture bro scripture is very black
and white there's no gray area and I
feel like the people that really just
really live live life bro it's very like
I'm doing this or nothing right or I'm
doing this or this it's not like well
maybe do this and I'll grab a little bit
of that here and I'll take a little bit
of this and yeah throw some of that on
top it's like no it's like we're going
for this life and that's it I tell my
wife it's either for are your food
stamps I'm gonna own the island or I'm
gonna sleep on it that's it there's no
in between I I think there's a power
that comes up I think about this often I
try to find ways to elegantly write
about it because um you know I've been
in kind of like the the mental health uh
I just got my mindfulness meditation
teacher certification and stuff so a lot
of my writing I try to write about
suicide in a way that's not cringey or
weird or like overly uh like be be
careful everyone I'm about to talk about
suicide like there's part of that that
feels like shitty um but I think
something that I keep coming to that was
so useful for me like back in the day
when we were going through those sorts
of things is dude and I heard somebody
else say on a podcast and it clicked
with with me because I made the decision
myself if you remove the option of
suicide like if you just commit in this
lifetime if you do one thing and you say
I will under no circumstance ever take
my life no matter how hard it gets no
matter how painful it gets I will not
ever give up my
life that option is now [__] off the
table dude 100% so now now what are you
gonna do when it gets hard that option
of like you know well maybe you start
that self- wallowing and I'm not trying
to make anybody who experiences that
feel bad I've been there Nate's been
there but I think removing it as it's it
is not an option it's suddenly like it
forces you to to look up and like maybe
maybe there's not a magical staircase of
light that lights up but maybe there's
like a speck of light in the dark and
it's [__] 20 miles away but like it's
something and you're like I know I can't
go back because I made the commitment
that I can never go into darkness start
walking towards that light and sure
enough more light will start show I
think what's really hard about that bro
is tell us when we were there things I'm
about to say right yeah yeah you don't
know like for me dude my life you don't
know dude you couldn't even fathom the
things I've been couldn't you have no
idea you have no idea right so so how do
we reach that
guy I try to do my best because the best
part about this bro is I love Peter bro
in the Bible because
Peter
was Peter was a dog bro like Peter had a
business Peter was doing all this stuff
and Peter was also breaking the rules
right Peter was Peter was working on
Sunday Peter wasn't supposed to be
working on Sunday right Peter um was
kind of I was I Peter was was supposed
to preach the gospel he was just this
super passionate guy and I
just I I I love that because I can
say I do this thing where heard 50 Cent
do it and I've started doing it ever
since he says when I'm in trouble I'm 50
Cent when I'm not I'm Curtis Jackson
okay so the best part about this is I
can talk about this but I'm a but I'm a
stunt writer right I'm not a preacher so
what does that mean I'll follow the same
rules that these guys have to follow
because I don't get up on Sunday and
stand in front of a camera and and get
in the the pull pit because that's a
responsibility I'm not ready for but the
cool part about this is I can share my
experiences but I'm still a stunt Rider
so if I mess it up or if I say something
I'm not supposed to say right um
when I realize okay and this is and and
for man I hope and I hope we serve
people in this moment that's I pray that
I pray that anybody that's it's in this
in this phase right now I hope that we I
hope that we can serve them as I have
this gun underneath my seat right oo
this
is this is what I needed to hear that I
wasn't ready to receive so if you're not
ready to receive it I apologize but this
is you know this here here goes my
testimony
um the weight that you feel that makes
you want to end the game is purpose and
responsibility okay so and behind that
is think about it if you want to end
your life you feel powerless you feel
hopeless right you imagine you don't
know how to ride a bull and somebody
straps you to it and you can't fall off
imagine that okay that's how you feel in
the most violent way right your teeth
are getting acting against the horns
like and I mean death we're talking
about death right so imagine that it's
getting stuck through your face like
that that type of um weakness and just
out of control and I know now again
highights 2020 that that responsibility
and that WG that I felt was purpose and
and just
like I don't want to say taking control
but like answering the call
right and I felt like I was so weak
check this out and again when you're in
this space you're already in you're
you're you're doing everything wrong
right so you're so weak mate to not take
this
responsibility that you can't even kill
yourself you don't have the balls you
can't even get this
right you can't even commit to this
you're not committing to
anything you can't even you want this
quote unquote but you won't even commit
to that otherwise it already be done
right so
again same type of mentality like I
talked about throughout the
years pointed in the wrong direction
okay
so we're showing here lack of commitment
to life lack of commitment to purpose
but also lack of commitment to decision
you're not neate make the decision then
let's get it
done right so but how hard is that to
hear in that moment like I'll never
forget I have a friend who you know Jay
curell right and I'm doing this and I'm
drinking and I'm smoking and I'm showing
up drunk driving at his house and you
know halfway you know hanging out the
door I'm going to kill myself he like do
it
[__] you
won't and if you do I won't be at your
funeral and man that just hit me like a
ton of bricks
bro just like he's right like I won't
right so what is this cry for help right
so and we can get so deep into this
right um the
the lack of I didn't lack you know
fatherhood but just like who was there's
a book anybody that's it's into
scripture or or just wants to explore
spirituality while the heart it's a book
on spiritual masculinity references the
Bible uh his name is John Eldridge he
uses
a a uh term and he says who who will
give the man his name right and he says
the father gives the man his name what
does that mean
this this last name that you wear on
your back this is what we represent
what's that word represent like I talked
about before something to represent this
is what we do this is how we handle [__]
this is how when things get tough this
is where you go right you you come to
the house we do this we have this we you
know we go so there's
no what's the coping mechanisms there is
none in place right it's just this is
hard exit this is hard exit but where
does this come from right lack of
structure within coming
from ideally we' get it from our fathers
right so this is why the same thing from
the bike down to the suicide I would
rather this I would rather die than this
right so for me I would rather die than
not feel like I gave my son enough and
of course he's going to go through his
own right but my job is to hey you're
four for the next 16 years before you
have to stick this sword in this
dragon's neck we're going to sharpen it
every day bro we're going to sharpen it
every day so when you go to stick it in
its neck it goes all the way through bro
and you don't have no problems right
so that is the harsher version of it the
more light version I would say is like
imagine there's a book that's written
about your life and it's it's already
done and it's already written okay so if
when this book says even at the very
beginning I carefully knitted you in
your mother's womb and I knew you
beforehand okay so if I have a place
here okay it's just very simple right
I'm not again I'm not a preacher okay
this is what I read here we go this is
what helps me if I have a place here and
these things are already done scripture
says if I do this then this happens if I
do this and this is a good life if I do
right it's stting
why do I need to go like my purpose is
already chosen for me at these but again
we have this idea that we think we know
this kind of stuff right Jake like I
know I got purpose here and and all this
but I really got to find it and I really
got to do it and I really got to make a
lot of money and I really got to make
sure I'm successful and all this kind of
stuff but it's like but you keep leaning
on yourself it's already done right if
it's already
planned okay and and I'm going to I have
one more thing after this to land the
plane okay if it's already
done just step into it right so again
there Nate was same mentality he's going
down there all he has to do is turn I
don't have to change at all nothing
about me CH I'm still a dog bro I still
barely sleep I still train like a
professional athlete I haven't rode in
two years nothing about me has changed
I'd still rather die than this nothing
has changed okay just step into it
answer the call the the call the call
happens every single day all you have to
do is answer it that is the weight that
we're feeling is that we feel like men
are designed to have a place here right
we're designed to be inspirational quote
unquote that's why we look at all these
other guys why do we get jealous if you
didn't believe that you were supposed to
be like that you wouldn't get jealous
okay so imagine things are already
planned out and all you have to do is is
step into it okay and for anybody that
that is thinks I'm cuckoo totally fine
all I ask is what can we argue that if
you followed the Ten Commandments which
is are just the general rules you could
argue that you could live a better life
that's all I'm going to say okay we can
argue that right you know you're not
going to steal you're not going to kill
you're not going to commit adultery do
all these things very basic um you could
have a better life and imagine you get
all the way to the end and you find out
it's not true true let's just say that
okay we find out this is all [__]
okay you can look back and be like well
[__] at least I live a good life while I
was here right at least I was good to
other people right treat your neighbor
as yourself but here's the nightmare
imagine you get all the way to the end
and you find out and you didn't follow
the rules right or you just like did
whatever you wanted to do and and you
were just wild and you were just
outdoing girls and doing all this stuff
and and you know sleeping with people's
wives like I was and and all this and
then you get to the end and you find out
oh [__] this was
real oh my God like look where I'm
headed not only look where I'm headed
but look at all of the heads right look
at this like metaphorically that I've
taken and people's lives that I've
ruined bro if somebody if some if
another man slept with my wife bro I I I
don't know what I would do bro like I I
I truly don't know if I kid stomach that
right it was like just a like I was
there just like oh no no no problem like
yeah no don't worries don't worry about
it yeah he's not here
like so that is just like and and the
reason I'm I know I'm ranting but I just
want to I just want to give credit where
credit is due right
because people are going to look on
these old pods well I remember that guy
whatever yeah whatever and it's like
here's a new version of him you you know
yeah yeah absolutely I mean I think uh
not that the place where you and I both
were at in those podcast was still a
great spot especially for a couple gents
at that age and especially for um you
know just for both of us for you know
the past that we had before so we were
just kind of going through things out
loud in a lot of ways um and now I love
the perspective that you're at I love
like where you've arrived it's it's so
beautiful dude it's like I feel like
everything is trying to tell us in some
way stop thinking about yourself and
serve other people like serve where you
can reach and you hear it and you hear
it and you hear it and then like think
about it yeah yeah it's and the and the
the thing that I mean you know is that
we can all agree most of the time that
it feels good why is it that our brain
is wired for
that again like oh let's think about
coincidence you know what I mean like
and also too
okay it's a pride thing okay we have
this like again these beautiful
beautiful beautiful traits built into us
that we go this way with
okay when I show up right and if I
have I mean bro I
went I'm I'm willing to wear I would I
I'm more willing right let's just say I
was in a bad situation I'm more willing
to wear rags to have my wife and kids
dress nicely right all day yeah I I am
far more prideful and going yo I'm take
I'm taking care of that [__] right like
but you think about it think about what
I just said yeah I'm taking care of that
[__] and think about but then the self-
serving ego at in in that saying that
same sentence right like yeah look at my
car I'm taking care of that [__] yeah
look at my car like look at my look at
my look at my money look at my this look
at my that look my watch like look at
all this right
and think of how much more depth that's
there when you're really again because
it's
like that same mentality I'm not going
bro you're not GNA die for a watch bro
the difference is when I say I'm taking
care of my [__] I'm I'll die for this
right here right now right like if
somebody comes and there's a situation
I'm I'm no problem taking a bullet when
someone comes and like give me your
watch like bet here take it right like
no problem yeah yeah absolutely bro you
want the here let me give you this two
like what what are you assigning value
to exactly so Jake I'm I'm really in a
place bro where I'm trying to
take and this is perfect we're building
my bio for the front
um I'm really trying
to build the ex exact life that I want
based upon this story that I've always
told as everyone's seen on my Instagram
the underdog right the guy that never
quits the guy that rolls around on the
concrete and never made a single dollar
from it never had a problem get back up
and getting right back on I'm trying to
build that narrative by building the
exact life I want by following these
rules and then when I get there saying
that these the rules I
followed I feel like that's a pretty
simple way to put it right he like well
you know why do you believe that well
this says it right here bro this is why
I believe well like and you could also
like you now realize you could make the
most legitimate impact that way when
it's not so much like I'm not trying to
like you know there's this ego side of
like dude do what I did you're just like
me I see myself and you and you know
there's helpful ways into connecting
with people with that but one thing I
love about any sort of spirituality is
not
like um like like let let me bite-size
this for you and packages for you
interpret it for you it's like no hey
man this this scripture this book worked
for me just give it a read read this
yeah like check this out again again
right the argument the argument that I
always make is can we argue that if you
follow these rules you would probably
live a better life right even if you
wanted to use it selfishly if you read
this stuff as affirmations you would
believe in yourself more yeah
do you see a man competent in his work
he will serve before
Kings can we not say that's a great
affirmation to
read how do you how do you get to the
people and I wonder if your answer is
changed like what you would have said a
couple years
back a lot of times people even having
these conversations are participating in
these conversations I mean you probably
notice it in your everyday life I mean
really anybody who is has like Christian
conversations in public spiritual
conversations in public if there's
somebody who like they consider
themselves an atheist or like God isn't
their thing like they they cannot even
like it just seems so foreign what
you're talking they can't contribute it
makes them uncomfortable um what what is
your I like to try to speak to people
like hey you think that this is
something that only spiritual people
talk about you think that like the
things we're talking about the mental
quarrels only has to do with like the
Bible and what Jesus did it's like no
this stuff is is a a diagram
it's a a blueprint for a human
experience and it saddens me I I wonder
how you think about it or like maybe how
you would talk to them in these days it
saddens me when people are like dude
keep that [__] away from me and then
they're still suffering they're still
going taking antidepressant they're
still exactly not saying Jesus will
solve all your problems that's not what
I'm trying to
say this isn't just for religious for
Spiritual and I want to be hum open and
transparent saying Jesus won't solve all
your problems that's that's that's a
great way to start yeah is no absolutely
bro I here's the thing this is oh this
is what I love about this bro is I know
people and this is not a holier than
thou statement right like I'm not oh I'm
better I know people that have been in
the church for 10 15 years longer than
me and the fruit that I see is is is so
much sweeter because I believe so much
more because I met God in the trenches
they met God because their parents told
them
to okay that's why I'm so passionate
about this because when there was no one
left nothing left and I was about to end
it all that's when this thing happens
and it like the light kicks on or
something right it's like the the and
again there it is Jake the same
mentality if I don't I'm the I'm the guy
used to be the guy okay are we drinking
all right cool well let's block out this
time because I'm gonna block out right
like oh no no no no we're just coming
out for drinks all right cool call me
when you guys are done we get back to
the house because I'll be passed out
right the mentality has always been the
same I've always been extreme and that
is the best part about it is because I
don't feel like you can properly squeeze
the juice out of something unless you
are extreme so with that being
said the people that and this is not a
direct answer to your question but I'm
trying to lay the foundation the people
that are very like like I don't believe
in anything that's totally fine and
again I I don't I truly don't care what
people believe I'm not trying to force
you to convert any but either I just no
no but like but like if you don't
believe in anything no kidding you
haven't exhausted anything yet go to the
other side I challenge you go there go
there go there go to the dark side see
how you like it go there first that's
where I went right but it's like when
you're in the
middle not you you can't believe because
nothing has happened to make you believe
imagine you met the devil At His Feet
you're going to believe
now you see what I'm saying so that's
why I just always tell people whatever
that is there explore that thing very
very harsh reality I was in like a men's
group of these guys and they were
talking about and we talked about this
before kind of like dabbling in porn
right and it's like you know yeah it's
just not that big of a deal it's only a
couple times a week I'm like watch it
for eight hours a
day you don't want to kick the you don't
want to kick the habit because you your
whole life and again this is like this
is where I'm going to sound like I'm
trying not to but this is where that
like you the the locker room talk comes
in right and and it's like I'm not a I'm
not a pre I'm a stunt Rider right I'm
not a preacher I'm a stunt riter but I'm
also I'm this is what got me here right
this is what got me good on the bike
this is what got me you know in the
business and all these things
is you're dabbling everywhere right
you're you dabble in the diet that's why
you're overweight you dabble in the gym
that's why you're out of shape you're
dabble in your marriage that's why your
wife's unhappy you're dabble with your
kids because that's why they don't
listen to you and it's not that they
have to listen but they they listen when
they respect you right the kids don't
listen to you every everything's half
ass so of course you don't need to kick
this habit because you're half F in this
too I didn't half FD because I was
watching porn all the time on the Max on
the way home from from Nike like my job
literally oh just not even doing just
watching it just for entertainment
that's crazy by the way that's insane
fully
submerged in
it but I only believe now in the light
because I was fully submerged in the
darkness but I had to go there and you
know I'm not to Anchor us just on the
point in fact but you don't watch porn
now right absolutely not no bro if I'm
not if if I'm not bro I mean I'm fully
um even times when my wife and I are
still having sex I still practice seor
retention yeah yeah well so I I want to
point it out just because I'm sure
there's tons of people if somebody's
listening right now when they are the
person who's on the Metro watching porn
they can't get enough of it I mean dude
how many posts on Reddit you see
nowadays of kids just like I can't stop
watching porn help yeah and so it I
wouldn't say that the poll was like that
like it was an addiction I I would 100%
because I was with so many partners at
that time that the pull to watch it on
my screen was not an addiction but it
was just like sex is my life kind of you
know what I mean it was like well yeah
like right after this I'm going home to
meet somebody and then later meet
somebody else and it's like it was just
so like it was just like um it was just
like our caffeine right it's like no do
I need you get it right this second no
but like yeah we're going to the gas
station in a half hour you know what I
mean so it wasn't like I had this like I
wasn't addicted to porn but sex was a
huge part of my life so it was like oh
well yeah sex is happening so let's
watch it you know what I mean yeah yeah
I I get you well so I I think I I try to
see it nowadays kind of as like a I know
I realize it didn't answer your question
but kind of what I would like to say
within that before was like explore one
of the two right because the more you
stay in the middle and we know this
Drake right it's like the cold punch
thing it's like if you put one foot in
you never really get in you know what I
mean get the DN
but okay so if you don't want to come
here check out the other side first see
what they have to offer right it's like
one of those things where it's like
you're an employer be like hey you think
you think the grass is greener go ahead
and check it out when ready to come back
we'll be here waiting for you right
that's kind of how I like to put it
because again it makes me very like I
don't want to push this thing on you but
I know what it's like to be there okay
and also too for anyone listening I
don't want to I don't really push a
religion so it's like I push having a
relationship with reading this like what
does this mean to you when you when it
hits your brain and when it hits your
head and when it hits your lips like
what does it mean to your life when it
comes out not like you need to be
Christian you need to be Catholic you
need to be Muslim you need to be this
this like I don't subscribe to that
right I go to a Christian church but I
don't say like you need Christianity in
your life like I don't I'm not that guy
right so I'm the guy that's like read
this book and whatever comes good out of
here for you that you can take to
benefit your life because I G 110% say
that your life will change for the
better see what happens well and and
it's kind of fascinating like the way
that the scriptures are interpreted
interpreted at different points in our
lives like so they
that right now is profound to them and
then they read it 5 years it's like it's
also profound but it means something
completely different it's somehow with
that stuff there is a weird
synchronistic nature of when you hear
things it kind of like Wiggles its way
around obstacles inside you and like
penetrates where it's supposed to and
gives you a little bit of Hope to
continue on and that's how like I feel
like all wisdom has been right you're
like it's like you read a book for the
second time and it was different than
you read it the first time you know what
I mean I feel like same kind of IDE so
yeah I I feel like that's the only way I
feel like to answer your question
without like you know coming at people's
necks you know what I mean is like yo
just try CU at this point I feel like
the people that are that waffle again
they're waffling everywhere right it's
like the same idea like the whole men's
group thing we're talking about kind of
like drinking um you know and for for me
like I haven't had a drop in alcohol in
like I think almost nine years I'm going
on N no no like no sips no like oh this
and that no no nothing um and
I um I just I say I'm like just do it
that's what we're called to do right
like imagine 50 years ago 60 years ago
or whatever and I'm not a history not
okay I'm a stunt writer um these kids
were lying about their age to storm on
the beaches knowing their fate was to
get shot in the head like that is the
type of passion that we all carried not
that long ago and now it's like we're
just dull right right like everything is
just dull and we're constantly being
diminished by this on a daily basis
right and you're just you're just
pouring garbage into again what we're
supposed to believe is the only true
thing that matters here right like on
this Earth this is the most important
thing that you possess and you dump you
fill it with garbage every single day
not only do you f with garbage you're
supposed to move it you don't you're
supposed to fuel it you don't right like
all these things and
I just feel like passion is the thing
that people are like God this guy's nuts
me right and it's like that's what
you're missing right like the people
that again I've always dealt with this
criticism of like you're so extreme
right like the food the this the that
and it's
like it's actually passion right
wouldn't it be awesome for you in your
life how much would your life change if
you believed in something as much as I
do right like even food bro I get I get
I will talk like this and how we're
having this conversation about steak
like imagine all how like how much how
much would this experience change for
you if you were that passionate about
everything that you thought about that
you loved and that you did right now we
can now we're just like getting into the
worldly stuff like imagine how your
everyday life would change if you're
just so passionate about everything
right that's what's changed my life I
knew that a job was not for me right the
traditional way that I was doing it
right I was a bartender that didn't
drink I'm sitting here saying I don't
represent this I don't believe in this
but here you go pal
right same idea I'm so passionate about
this that I'm not I'd rather be
broke here's a financial death here we
go same mentality I'd rather be broke
than do this
right so but what's the underlying part
of it is finding the juice bro finding
the Gusto letting the dog out right like
that's what I feel like I'm trying to
represent is that everything that I
believe to be true about this life or
about how to live a good life or what I
believe life is supposed to be that
people looked at me and like dude that
guy's a dog off the leash
bro that's what I want to represent
you know you know what I think you did
um you know being being you know a
self-certified intense person let's say
you know you're an extreme person um I
intense is a word I use for myself
that's kind of the same thing int yeah
but there's nothing wrong with it but so
I I think what can happen is when we
notice we are that sometimes it we want
to lessen ourselves or we want to kind
of like put a shade or a blanket over
our shining and sometimes I'm going to
relate this to chakras I know I hope
this isn't too big of a jump for people
but like when you're just thinking about
busting a nut eating the best you know
most delicious taste bud appealing food
whatever like you see you know everybody
knows a basic level of chakras you got
your different colors say you got seven
of them and each one you know is you
know your thoughts of the future your
ability to speak the truth you know your
confidence is somewhere down here
whatever I think a lot of times extreme
people when they're denying their
purpose when they're trying to shut up
uh the the nature the you know God's
invitation to be as big as they should
be as expansive as they're capable of
being we kind of like shove and keep
that energy inside and I think sometimes
it get shoved into chakras of like
sexual pleasure of um wanting to just
feel Comfort like the second we get
hungry we don't like that because it's
trying to get us out of our comfort zone
so we just keep eating you know um we
just get shoved into our lower like
monkey mind chakras and we have all this
enery energy that's trying to go up to
the other chakras and express itself and
like change the world around us like
change physical reality through our
action you know but it's being just
squeezed down here and nowadays we got
our magic rectangle you know and this
thing is really good for keeping that
energy right down it's a it's a black
hole right and a great thing to what you
said um Victor Frankle a
man he what's he say a man who lackes
purpose will seek pleasure pleasure
Comfort okay um
let's just go to like worldly success
right let's argue the idea of like the
you know the intensity and like the guru
right what do they say like you got to
do this you got to do that there's no
other option like all these like
motivational
speeches scripture literally says right
so this is why I argue for the extremism
the passion the intensity bro scripture
literally says if your eye causes you to
sin gouge it out right so it's like
think remember like what what we used to
do like you know we got to cut the dead
weight like you know like whatever's
holding us back it's got to go friends
family everything's got to go right the
food's got to go like the things got to
go you know what I mean like but it's
like it's you see the alignment there
you know what I mean like when you when
you bro and also too when you're really
in your lane and you're really in your
bag this just comes natural you just
start ignoring stuff on accident you
know what I mean you stop seeing things
on like on accident for instance right I
believe people say the most important
thing in this life is time we can argue
that I'd say it's perspective and what
do I mean by that how two people can sit
in the same exact room and experience
two different
things the time is ticking right but the
perspective may never change right so
imagine like you're like oh my gosh I
really got 80 years here this is crazy
and the other person's like and oh my
God my 80 years is just like diminishing
as we speak you know what I mean who's
going to live a different life right or
for instance you know I'm sitting in the
car with my dad the other day and um I
was like did you see that guy looking at
me like you know whatever and I'm like
I'm like or like you know that guy's got
a problem and I'm like I didn't even see
him like which guy dude this happens to
me all the time so the so the glasses
right the lenses in which you see things
the most powerful thing that you can
grasp onto in this life and then with
that let's be passionate about what lens
you're putting on bro wouldn't you again
would can't we just say that if you just
woke up and you were as passionate about
waiting until 2 P.M to eat a steak as me
like bro I'm so Juiced to wait all day
and then have it I'm like but this is
the this is the act of gratitude which
is the actual key to raising the vibe
right like the highest form of energy is
gratitude there is nothing in this
moment that gets better than
this tell me if you can have as many of
those moments as possible even when
there's pain right right dude my son you
know having a huge meltdown tantrum
doing all this stuff right and it's just
it's just open the door he's not ready
open the door he's not ready he's
pounding on the door all these things
and we sit down and he breaks down and
we're there and we're like do you like
having this it's like there is nothing
in this moment that is better than this
right so how many of those moments can
you collect but the but what I see is
and it's and again broadening out the
metaphor to like even worldly success
right and I want to kind of connect
world and spiritual is how often do we
get to that pain the Tantrum right the
metaphorical tantrum close the door or
let him cry it out see in an
hour we do that with the other things
that we work on right close the door
whatever I'll get on my phone it can
happen tomorrow it can happen this day
it can happen that day whatever I'll put
it off I'll put it off I'll put it off
and
then we're lacking those moments of
right now nothing is better than this
because we have yet to like go through
the fight that gets there and this is
where I'm talking about how in the
difficulty is
where the winning actually happens and
that's where it is and so um again
scripture said you will rejoice in your
suffering right so I just but the but
the key to it is that it has to be seen
through so all these moments like bro
imagine the the people that look back
and they go that and you know like
marriage
they they look all the way down their
life and they look back on everything
they created and we're like damn
remember those times we almost threw in
the
towel like and here's all our
grandkids and we almost threw in the
towel we almost
quit there's nothing in this moment that
is better than this right so I think
that the biggest thing that has changed
since we did the last podcast and I feel
like that's a subject we're on is like
almost like Evolution right is my
perspective on life has just immensely
shifted right um and that is through and
only through massive massive massive
trial massive right um I like to tell a
story because I like to again give
credit where credit is due I quit my job
like we were talking about before um I
was miserable right and I have the the
the receipts to back it up um that every
I was just miserable I was just like
again Jake I'm right here bro I am
cleaning um I'm doing stain removal in
car seats I'm doing stain
removal um in in at these dealerships
and I look at myself and I say if this
this is all that is in the plan I'd
rather
die same mentality right um get into a
fight with cly's Dad who I was working
for um didn't go to work the next day
had $7 in my bank account okay
and I kept telling myself you've done it
your way for this long right let's try
something else okay so
if I believe in and again this is where
the thing that I said hey maybe you
don't believe but let's just try
right give this all you got and see what
happens and and and that's what it was I
gave it all I had I don't have to
believe myself I have to believe in
what's already written right I go to put
gas in the car I'm going to put 10 bucks
in nope fill it up you ain't got to
believe in you believe in that right
believe in what's already there believe
in that believe in the words you read
this morning right so this is the same
ideas which are um New Age ways which I
I was a part of my wife was a part of
and no offense to anybody that's there
at all um it just didn't work for me at
all I was always seeking something else
because it's like oh yeah who made these
rocks right like you know how did this
stuff get here right like even the
Creator created the man who created this
idea like you know what I mean so it's
like let me let me go all the way to the
end right let me be nasty Nate right let
me let me see if I can jump over my
handlebars at 70 on the highway when
there's two cars next to me right let me
do that with this okay and
so um
mixing that with Nasty Nate birthed the
life that I Live Now which is I make my
own money I live by my own rules I I own
my time if I don't want to do something
I don't have to right I've also changed
again my perspective of Jake that's the
biggest thing is I've changed my
perspective
on I'm and this is where the scripture I
was just reading the scripture with um
and if anybody's interested um I do have
run a men's group on Sundays Sunday
mornings at 6:00 AM uh PST Jay can link
that um and I was reading scripture with
my guys last week and it says a
scripture says that you cannot serve two
masters right and this is where people
get caught up in you know money's evil
money's evil no money's not evil uh
money's evil when it's your master which
means you change who you are as a man
for it right so if I'm gonna and this is
why I I again if you read these other
books that say your gift will you know
scriptures your gift will make room for
you it's already done it's already
written so if I think from that frame
right if I was and this is again like
shifting from New Age over to right here
people are like manifested you know
affirmations it's it's it's bro if I'm
I'm I'm this guy regardless of what's
going on right so that changed so much
for me that I actually people don't
understand is when I was broke I was
slave to money right like I didn't get
out of $7 in my bank account and and at
that point two dependents and a
stay-at-home wife and I didn't get out
of it to be financially independent
meaning I make my own money I'm not
financially free like oh I have to work
another day in my life but being
financially independent other than the
fact that I said if I'm constantly
thinking about this all the time and
it's eating me up and I can't sleep
because my account's negative money's my
master and imagine I'm mastered to
something that another man is pressing a
button and and bringing to life
this is where most Christians and most
people in general get caught up in the
in in being slave to money and again I'm
not saying that I don't have to work
another day in my life but what I'm
saying is is I'm not going to let my
life which is my mood my energy the way
that I operate which I am the the head
to the rest of my family I'm going to be
swayed and I'm going to change my mood
and change this and change that and
Dad's day is ruined which means
everybody else's day is ruined that's
how it goes because of a piece of
paper but because of that perspective
and mindset
shift bir the
business otherwise that would have never
happened I would have went back to what
I was doing and being slave to the
dollar I got to have it right this
second I got to have it right this
second I need a paycheck now right I I
need to go they have it guaranteed for
me let let me
no I was changing who I was right so
what what is your psychology with money
now like what like how do you like like
right now how do you think of money
compared to how you used to think of
money I think of it as a tool right I
think it of it as now is what are my
priorities okay my priority used to be
money and crazy enough I didn't have a
lot of it right and I don't want to make
lessons about money I want to talk about
about my limiting beliefs that kept me
where I was that with I feel like what
we're talking about is evolution that
was birthed through me coming to
scripture so which which birth worldly
sucess for me right like I'm at where
people right you kind of see what I'm
saying so I'm trying to follow The
Narrative of I'm evolving because I'm
following this and
here's all the trials I had talked about
suicide Just So for anybody that's
getting lost right talked about suicide
talked about like the the mental health
thing talked about the bike um and now I
feel like the last piece of it was like
okay like if you think you're him then
like go make your own money you know
what I mean like because you know you
want that but again it was another thing
I wasn't committed like I'm doing gigs
on the side here and there it's fine
it's whatever and it's like I don't
expect also to full transparency I don't
expect anybody to one I'm not selling
anything so you know I get a couple
comments about that when I talk about
money on my YouTube um on my YouTube
videos we're like oh you sound like a
guru and I'm like dog did you forget I
don't have anything for sale this for
free you're welcome yeah and for
two if anything these are the people
that always have this like minimal
perspective I just told you I 10x my
income you should be happy for me if
you're watching my video Co yeah like
this this comment makes no
yeah it's like it really doesn't I'm
like bro for one I'm not selling
anything for two if you're if you watch
the whole damn thing what I just said
you think I'm a guru dog you should be
happy for me like what the hell yeah
it's it's weird to be jealous of a
stranger
succeeding crazy bro and I just and I
don't I'm not a successful person right
like I don't give credit to to I don't
and this is not something I really even
care about but I think the reason I talk
about it is because it handcuffs so many
people right we're handcuffed to the dog
we're handcuffed to the currency we're
handcuffed to the the rat race and it's
like you don't even actually have to do
it no one says you have to and I think a
big when I was first building my
business sorry my relationship with
money it's a
tool um I see it as time how now I'm not
interested I used to be interested in
stuff because that's what we see as
success right and this has been years
like I think it would probably say like
when I was 21 22 I'm like oh yeah I want
this car I want that car I want this I
want that until I realize that you can
buy your time instead right yeah and
that's and then now I realize okay if my
son was the same age as my daughter and
this is the the thing that always gets
me it's always nothing is more important
than this moment right now when I throw
my daughter in the air and I'm just like
doing and you know how like for like
when you have like a a pencil or a pen
you like and you go to pick up another
one in that first moment it's like this
is weird like right I'll throw my
daughter up in the air a couple minutes
and I'll go to pick up Jet and it's like
I go to use the same force and the same
Force doesn't bring the same height and
his rib cage is wider and I'm
like wow like that was just you and so
that that can't be purchased what is
more important than
that so when people say you know time
Freedom all this all that it is so again
intense and extreme and passionate that
I'm not even buying my time I'm buying
the ability to be able to feel how wide
my son's rib cage is
today that's how deep this [__] is to me
right and you cannot have this typ type
of depth unless you have been so low
that you appreciate the that on that
little on that little of a level that
when I do business and I personally
think family men are the best men to do
business with and this is why I take it
so serious is because yeah you're doing
business with me but you're putting food
in my kids's mouth so guess what I'm
going to take care of you right and not
only am I going to take care of you I'm
going to take this business relationship
serious okay
so go ahead bro I mean I I just got
excited I I I just think it's like if
you consider money as energy as well you
know there I I feel like I get to a
point where I don't really want to be
involved with the energy of dudes who
are going to like [__] someone else's
wife I don't really want to do like even
though it has nothing to do like
absolutely nothing to do with our
transaction if I know outside of has
nothing to do with me that
that are it just starts to feel strange
to me and maybe that stuff isn't matter
to everybody else but I can't ignore
when I feel it and I notice it you know
and so I find myself wanting to distance
myself from from those but um yeah I
just think money money has energy to you
know accomplish and be present with
where you're really at that's a
[__] 100% bro yeah and I um again
just going along with like how I change
my perspective um I had like a
revelation where I mean bro things were
bad right like things were were not
doing I was not doing good financially I
was having a hard time getting clients
for video all this kind of stuff and I
remember the first month I made four
grand which was $1,500 under what we
needed for bills
and um and this was like two or three
years ago I can't remember and I just
remember my buddy
saying that's how much money he makes a
month and I'm
like even though I feel and this is
where you need these moments okay so
like anybody that's listening think back
on these moments where you can have
these and this is why I feel like people
waste this right we talk about before we
talking about trauma and all these
things and how we're just wallowing it
well you don't use it okay these moments
are moments that need to be used and
exhausted that for that four grand I
worked a day and a half but I couldn't
get any other worked and for that four
grand and my friend worked 20
days and in that moment I was like
you've already beat the game bro yeah
you
be you just have to but the but again
what it what happens when you are in a
low vibrational State you close yourself
off to possibilities right so what do
you do oh my God I only made four grand
I need $1,500 more to pay my bills I
don't know where I'm going to get it
from I just I'm a piece of [__] my
business doesn't work nobody wants to
pay me right what am I doing I'm close I
just was like dog I just made four grand
in a day and a half well what's I that
means I can
make uh uh in three days which is what I
used to work six I can make 12 Grand
that means I make 12 Grand a week like
whoa oh my I'm cooking now right but
it's like you don't even think like that
until you're out of that perspective out
of that state and scripture is what
helped me change that right a man a
man's gift will make room for
him like okay if I'm good at this the
clients are already there right like C
can I ask you something what do you
think about you can ask me whatever you
want I'm talking way too much bro no not
at all bro I this always how it is with
you and I man we always go on [__]
wonderful quests but um I start for my
PO potty mouth today too I didn't intend
to have that but no worries um uh
um okay so so I was going to ask
something and I've been wanting to
explore this I been kind of trying to
write about it um but I think you'd be a
good person to ask the whole like Law of
Attraction
manifestation this whole world I mean
you've mentioned new age a couple times
it's like really prevalent in in that
world and I noted like when I first
stumbled into it there was like years of
it being so fun so magic so great and
I'm so glad I did it but then after a
while I noticed that I would get to this
spot where I would I would go notice oh
I'm thinking I'm being negative I'm
thinking about the not the positive and
then that itself would go oh [__] oh
stop thinking about the bad stuff oh no
and then you get in this like weird like
where you basically start wallowing and
end up sitting on the ground and defeat
because you're like I'm just being
negative I've now just lost all my
progress of positive thoughts and I'm
only attracting bad stuff to me
basically you become afraid of your own
mind exactly how do
you what's your thoughts on that how do
we get out of that how do we not trip so
again I'm not a preacher I'm a stunt
writer so I don't have full
understanding of scripture but for what
from what I understand the enemy is
defeated foe okay which means that if
you believe in the light then the
actually like the not that the darkness
doesn't exist but it does not have power
okay so with that being said like my
wife has experienced spiritual attacks
she's had
um what is the thing where you're awake
but you can't move what is that um like
like Lucid dreamy when sleep
paralysis um isn't it sleep paralysis
yes so she's had sleep paralysis before
I believe so yeah so she's had spiritual
attacks before um and I have never
experienced that ever like I don't feel
like you know something's in a house or
this or bad energy or whatever and and
she was like God I wonder why and I was
like h honestly I don't believe in that
[__] I really don't I don't it doesn't
cross my mind any way shape or form that
do I believe that the enem is a fallen
angel yeah do I believe that there's
people out here that are that are evil
100% but like do I believe that that has
any effect on me whatsoever no not at
all so um I think it is belief Jake but
I think it's the belief in the right
thing right so the way I look at it is
and Christian men do this so much and
this bugs the [__] out of me bro bugs
the [__] out of me these guys give the
enemy so much credit bro like oh the
enemy is just really pulling me towards
the porn the enemy's really attacking my
finances and it's
like why does he deserve that credit
unplugged from that dude you're giv
energy like ex exactly so it's like and
again scripture says you cannot serve
two masters so in that moment you you're
George jenko said this on a podcast one
time he said you're in that moment when
you think like I was just explaining
you're serving the devil is that
something you want to do nah let me just
change a channel right so it's like it's
all the same ideas bro it just the
credit has to just be given in the
correct place and check this out again
why do most people when they do this
manifesting affirmations let me get to
where I want to
go why is there always like I I do a lot
of video stuff for guys in the day
trading industry and they're always
changing cars changing watches changing
this changing that new house new this
new
that what if that's not your grand
purpose my guy and that's why it's so
fleeting and that's why no matter what
you're driving it doesn't ma it doesn't
change how you feel because guess what
you brought it upon yourself but one
thing I do believe is that those powers
do exist right I believe in energy okay
I believe that all these things that we
talk about do exist but it's like be
careful what you ask for kind of thing
you know what I mean um I believe in all
that I believe that you can get what you
want I I'm in full belief of that but
what I know is that I already
experienced that and I asked for those
things I asked for the bike and I asked
for the cloud and I ask for the helmets
and I asked for all this [__] and
and and and it it it wasn't until again
I had kids that I was like there is
nothing
in this moment that is better than this
right and
um so I got what I asked for and then I
got what was truly meant for me and what
was truly meant for me was to
be a and then I was like okay so I want
to know
what that purpose is right not what I
have believed
to make of my own purpose you know you
know what I mean cuz I bro it can happen
I've seen it like I said but why is it
that these men that do scripture and I
mean really do do scripture there's this
dude Philip Anthony Mitchell who's just
a dog bro he was an ex drug dealer and
he is just a dog for scripture and he
just has the end same it's like ET but
like on steroids board like and like
he's calling out the truth like he's
reading stuff that other preachers shy
away from cuz it's like oh I don't want
to upset people on the gram and YouTube
and I don't we don't want to get people
out the doors that don't want to do
tithing anymore he's reading the truth
and within that it is just the most
powerful and beautiful thing but I mean
bro why is it that these guys have so
like you see him have so much
fulfillment he I remember a story he was
on a mission trip and he had a
revelation ever since he came back he's
never worn a color he wors all black he
doesn't want to draw attention to
himself he calls it a uniform he's like
this is my uniform this is why I believe
I'm not supposed to draw attention to
myself I'm supposed to show up this is a
job for me right but it's like why do
those men feel so like they seem so
fulfilled but all these dudes with the
this and the that and the flashy and the
colors and the pink shirts and and it
has nothing to do with fashion right but
it's like but when you're like doing
this thing to stand out or to be me or
to people better know me what not pull
up and all this like why is those
things why does it seem like those
things things are
always changing right and like being
like well D bro you just bought the
other car like last week like it's just
like what like what the hell like I
thought you like and it's like you were
doing that now you're doing this and
it's like because they're trying to find
something a foundation to stand on and
all the foundations that they're
building on are are not solid but then
you see the men that do have those
things but they're rooted in in
something solid they don't stand on that
right like bro I I I heard of ET thing
he said one time he said why you don't
think I don't post none of my cars you
don't think I have a Rolls-Royce he said
cuz I don't want people to go to the
dealership when they need to go to the
Bible yeah dude well well I mean how
much does our culture mess up with
trying to we puts all of our energy into
the image of success instead of like
learning what success could really mean
for us as an individual I mean as you
mentioned the fashion thing it's I can
relate with that man I think when when I
was you know at my most hurt inside I
was trying to be the loudest outside
with my fashion you were doing the most
[__] the hair and the this and the that
and the glasses and the piercings and
the this and yeah yeah I I don't want
attention I even I mean I mean if people
listening might remember I made I had
like a little like an accidental
clothing line for a few months I made
these you matter uh hoodies they have
the suicide number on the back and my
perception of even that is completely
different like I wouldn't even wear that
now because I didn't realize it back
then I was trying to make a statement
about myself or the person who wants to
wear like I support suicide rather than
like really dealing with what's going on
inside to where I don't have to run
around wearing a shirt like ask me about
suicide I'll teach you everything I'm a
pastor about it and instead I can just
heal from those things have my real
experience and then you know what
sometimes once in a while every 6 months
3 months whatever I'm at work having a
combo with a young guy 22 years old and
he's going through exactly what I went
through and I didn't need to wear a
hoodie saying ask me about it I would
just showed up and I was present in my
life exactly and those and then this is
what scripture says that's a Divine
appointment right like it's like you're
supped to be right where you're supposed
to be but no I love that bro but
honestly I really love the idea of
mixing cultured people with this because
we're the guys that can connect with
people right um like there's I feel like
a lot of preachers have a hard time
connecting with the younger generation
because all these guys know is that
they've been a preacher their whole life
right it's like but where are the guys
like me right that have been
encapsulated in
and just have been in the deepest depths
of sex and just all these types of
things and then
going there's a there's a quote that
says that that God doesn't call the
qualified he qualifies the called right
and it's like the fact that you're a
disaster the fact that you're the fact
that you're a
disaster actually means you're called
right because it's this is we are more
related this is psychological from a
from a positive standpoint and a
negative standpoint if you um hire a guy
at a Ferrari dealership you say hey dude
I'm going to give you this key to this
car you can drive it and you can drive
it it's yours if you sell this many X
cars a month and if you don't I'm going
to take it away he sells those cars if
you hire him and you say hey if you sell
this many cars I'm going to give you
this car he may hit it he may not but I
guarantee once he's driving that thing
he will hold on to it right and so
um we are more connected and we dive
more towards pain right because that
would be something taken away from me
and that's considered pain what I'm
getting at is psychologically we
communicate better through pain right
the guys that that like make it
financially they there's this mutual
respect there because they're like oh I
know what I went through like and he
went and he went like he that means he
went through that too right and that's
where you see the camaraderie within
that you're like why rich people always
hang out with each other it's like bro
it's it's a camaraderie there because
it's like you don't know what it's like
to build something like this right think
about military people going through the
same
stuff so it's the same thing with kind
of what I'm saying is that's why I love
being in this position
because when I'm like oh man I know I
know where you are like and when I speak
people are like God I feel that like now
I'm connected to you think about it you
listen to people you respect right
you're like yeah you've been a preacher
your whole life bro come on like nobody
wants to hear all that but it's like oh
Nate was I remember when he was at the
thing I remember he's at the L the the
LCC party and and he was breaking the
bottles over the thing because his his
ex-girlfriend is making out with some
some dude and he cheated on her but now
she's with somebody else but he's pissed
off for some reason drunk breaking
bottles yeah that same he was doing yeah
that same guy yeah now he wants to talk
about this yeah like or like bro I mean
being as good as I am on the bike like
it's automatic respect these people I
have these people's respect so it's like
yeah maybe if Joe Schmo that's not good
they don't want to hear what he has to
say but 90% of people don't care about
what I'm talking about now but the 10%
Jesus says I'll leave 99 to save the one
right so if I can get 1% if I can get
one person Bro think about that Branch
out right that's why parenting is so
important to me and why I'm telling I'm
trying to tell people especially parents
there's nothing more important in this
life you'll do than to be a parent think
of a branch out that happens my son okay
I'm having a lot of kids bro I don't
know why my wife thinks about that but
I'm having a lot of kids yeah let we
have three we have she says four she
said she's fine with four I I would like
far more than five okay but but think
about that okay think about how if I
just impact my son and I just give him
everything he needs to go out and just
face these battles and to live a good
life and to be a good man then he has
five kids hopefully right then my
daughter has five kids hopefully then my
other daughter has five kids hopefully
and then they go out and they be like me
and they want to be like you know what I
was I'm a I'm a little shy to talk about
this because it's not my normal M Mo and
it's mostly like yeah nasty nay Save the
Day but this is what actually changed my
life and I want to share it with you
imagine my
25 little little minions go out and do
that and then how many lives they change
yeah okay so this is what the meaning of
life is we just have got it
confused well you uh have you heard of
Ken Wilbur he's like a spiritual he
writes um like ingal Theory I don't he's
a strange he's like a bald dude he wears
a wig nowadays he's like he's it's funny
to see but anyway he uh he talks about
um you know in Spiritual Awakening there
is uh like this spiritual Evolution that
becomes apparent like you wake up to
whatever version of your spiritual
awakening is some people their Spiritual
Awakening is just like holy [__] the
government like gave me a name when I
was like this isn't my name I was given
this name and the government loes like
sometimes it's just that level but any
sort of Awakening especially Spiritual
Awakening it seem it's become so
apparent oh yeah evolution is happening
and I had to become aware of those
things that I was unconscious to of of
course I'm I'm developing I'm growing
when I'm 60 years old I'm going to be a
wholly different person right but um
along with that Awakening something that
Ken Wilbur points out that is just so
juicy to me
is spiritual maturing spiritual growing
up like and it's something that we
actually have to put effort into it's
like you know as as guys we come a
certain age you know you get 14 15
whatever you hit puberty your body just
does this and then you're along for the
ride and your personality changes right
I think I've heard this yeah the
universe does this it's like without
like and then you got to change yourself
to like biology yeah all these things
right it's biology is automatic yeah
yeah but there's also so interest we
could freaking become blind and like
turn an eye turn turn a blind eye to the
fact that we actually have to insert a a
a growing up a maturing of our spiritual
selves too and that doesn't just happen
our society doesn't have rituals and
traditions that really allow that to
happen so if we never assert our own
authority over it we might be 48 years
old and we're still crying about like
when that guy took away our yellow
kickball and when we were 13
yeah there's there's 100% bro yeah
there's a scripture that says um how
long it says this is the translation I
have is the new English like new NLT
which is like the very very very like
English version of it but in mine it
says you simpletons how long will you be
simple and it's like that's how I look
at like the way that we're living now
right this life is about depth bro like
I said when I think about money I don't
think about money bro I don't think
about stuff I think about if I make
enough I can buy the the time to feel my
son's rib cage bro like and I think and
I think and people will be like and
people that are sleeping will be like
this guy is a is a psychopath this guy
is nuts this guy's off as rocker he
needs meds he needs help guess what I
already took him they didn't work
um he this is the level of depth that
you that you got to grasp to be able to
like really unlock what this life is bro
and it truly is just about giving
everything for something right and I
think that's where the happy men quote
unquote happy that's where the happy men
are
is Fighting For A Cause right and that's
why I was talking about the war you know
50 years ago these kids were like bro
these kids know as soon as I jump off
this boat I'm getting shot in the head
they were they were doing it anyways
yeah and and the craziest part is is
again how much new ages changed it was
for no glory nobody knew who these guys
were they didn't get Marty they didn't
go in the paper sure there was like a
big ass list of all these kids that that
risked their life but it was like they
weren Heroes they were doing what they
were supposed to
do we need especially as men is to get
back to doing what we're supposed to do
okay I I sent this um this for my men's
group a group a message in the chat the
other day most of the stuff that we're
supposed to do we will never receive
credit for but that's what you're
supposed to do right it's like planting
a tree you'll probably never see that
tree ever reach his full potential and
that's the same idea I'm talking about
with being a man being a father and
raising children is to bury and plant
fruit that you never ever
see and then instilling your son to do
the same thing and that's how you create
strong generations and I'm going to tell
you exactly why I believe that right now
more than ever this is the most
important thing that any father any man
can be doing is investing not into it
his career but into his family into his
children and if you have a son investing
in your son cuz I'm telling you with AI
and all the [__] that's going on
right now this world as generation going
to go on is going to get harder and
harder and harder to navigate mentally
and spiritually if you are not raising
dogs your lineage is doomed I'm telling
you that right now I'm calling my shot
it's 20 January 25th 2025 if you are not
raising Warriors in your homes sons and
daughters that that I have discernment
of I'm not doing this I'm not doing that
I'm not going there I'm not putting
myself on the internet to do this or do
that your lineage is doomed I'm saying
that right now ai is is AI is literally
a two-day old baby and it's already the
scariest show I've ever seen in my life
yeah pretty much every day in advance is
that a way that we couldn't fathom the
week before I saw something the other
day that said that AI is already done
with us like people think like oh this
is so dangerous AI is learning from us
no AI is already done learning from us
it's been done learning from us from the
first couple months it's it already
gathered everything that it needed from
All Humans now it's building upon its
own thing so
again we are headed to what I see
towards Wall-E you remember Wall-E I
love W here okay so that movie that
movie that's where we're headed so again
if you don't want to get swallowed up if
you don't want to see your Generations
get swallowed up you need to be raising
dogs well I mean it's actually
interesting to think I think you are
touching on a vibration that is uh
present in the culture I think uh the
last few months we've seen a lot more
like dudes less afraid to say things out
loud um more like encouraging each other
like stand up um you know don't like
nobody's coming to save you that that
whole thing has seemed like the last few
months like people are really unafraid
of that and I think it's important I
think it's useful and I think like the
bottom line is our young Med [__]
need people to look up to so it's like
100% what are you what are you doing you
know like yeah and real quick before you
skip that I want to touch on that
because there is a very fine line and
this is where like you said there's been
a big thing of men standing up to do
this if you are involved in this stuff
on the internet you need to have
discernment why because I saw one of the
biggest men's pages that I've ever seen
and every single piece of content that
goes viral is about being a sad
boy no one cares about us no one cares
about our feelings and these are the
most viral posts and on top of that this
guy's selling something on top of that
so he's doing sad boy [__] going viral
and then selling something this does not
serve you no this does not serve you
this keeps you exactly where you are
guess what we're going to do we're all
going to get together we're all going to
talk about how hard it is and that's
where we're going to stay guess what
find our identity there thank you okay
so a lot of as much as you believe that
some of this that again there goes the
pain what did I say it's relative we
relate to it because of the pain but
what is the after right this exactly
what I was saying before most people
don't see progress in life because they
stop at the pain He Man Yeah I love this
dude's page bro he's always posting
these videos is like dude there was this
guy that I even bought a sweatshirt I
had to unfollow him cuz everything about
was that it's so hard not to be an
alcoholic I message him I'm like you got
to stop being a [__] bro like you
either want this or you want that you
either want to be a standup guy and be a
good dad and this is it bro I firmly
believe you can change your life in an
instant
imagine bro this is everything is
metaphorical is so beautiful okay
imagine for anybody and I have not yet I
need to be baptized
we believe as Christians when you get
baptized you get dipped in the water you
get pulled up you're fully renewed
everything is renewed right if I'm
created in God's image which scripture
says so why can I not Snap My Fingers
close my eyes open them and I'm a
completely new person why is that not
possible this thing here's your
affirmations this thing no longer has a
hold of
me okay
if most of the time a lot of our actions
don't align with what we say we want
right so
if I say I want to be a good dad I want
to be this I want to be that I want to
blah blah blah
blah why am I
fighting this thing and then I realize
I'm like oh you're selling sweatshirts
oh these videos go viral oh and it's
like this corny ass [__] like oh I
really want to tell my wife how I'm
doing
but and just pulls a like this white
mask over his face better walk walk out
the door it's like that stop watching
this content this does not serve you
okay again most people cannot be honest
enough with themselves or even want to
hear me say this because you probably
bought his sweatshirt that watch the
chain do I believe that he probably had
good intentions starting out absolutely
because that spoke to somebody and they
may be got it together but this
continuous over and over and over and
over again guess what I was reading the
same scripture the other day and
scripture says
um oh man I'm so sorry
um got to pull it
up God blesses those who whose hearts
are pure okay so what I wanted to say
with that is people believe that our
actions are what's on trial no your
heart is on trial and guess what nobody
can see that but you right so even if
the intention and again this is for men
have discernment even if the intention
with whatever this guy had going on
started out good hey I'm dealing with
this I want to share it I'm getting
through it but then all of a sudden when
you start to see this trend Oh
weird there's there's oh oh he's got oh
he's got some stuff for sale weird oh
all these sad boy videos go
viral Oh weird there all of a sudden he
stopped posting his progress and he's
replaying the most viral videos and he's
recording them in a different way
where's the progress my guy but guess
what most people the Sheep the 99% they
don't want to see progress they want to
see somebody where they're at which
means it's what Jake relatable y you see
the chain here so I pray that that man
has a clean heart that's what I pray for
right so that is another one of my
focuses cuz I realize I'm raising my
children here I'm doing this I'm doing
good right but it's like but where is my
heart at and I think that if this is
where the true success actually lies is
knowing even though I'm doing good
actions right um even though I'm giving
money to people on the street nobody
knows that what Bible says I'm not
supposed to tell anybody I'm doing that
Bible says I'm not supposed to put that
on the internet right what is the
intention did you give the money away
because you thought it was a good idea
but yeah why why do we record it why' we
have to do that so the action is in the
right but that's the actions are not
being judged the heart is being judged
right so that that was just a metaphor
of I'm trying to do everything even in
my good deeds as I raise my son and my
daughter and my other daughter and i' be
a good husband to my
wife Lord help me do that that um be a
good husband to my wife that I'm not
doing this for my own thing like look at
me look what I've done with my kids
right but this can only happen and my
friends will tell you Brandon will tell
you I am the most self-accountable
person ever even when things are going
right I'm like what am I doing wrong
here right like and so most people would
look at even Brandon he like dog why are
you so hard on yourself I'm like cuz I
just know accountability is the way like
and again extreme intense accountability
right I don't want people to look at me
and go oh yeah your kids are this and
your kids are that and we go yeah well
that's why I'm doing it no I want my
heart to be pure so then when this
Branch out happens it happens in good
faith right it doesn't happen because it
was a show you know what I mean well do
you okay so what I think that people he
kind of already said it earlier but like
people put their energy into their image
so much and I've been there you've been
there
how do we how do we notice when we're
doing that how do we notice when we're
like it's it's kind of that same little
extrem accountability bro well have you
ever seen what
people like I feel like I'm going to use
females just because I feel like they're
an easy low hanging fruit example like
you watch videos of like like a drunk
girl being recorded on you know her
party Street or whatever like like the
Haka situation um like suddenly they are
a person they're an expression of who
they are and then suddenly they realize
someone's recording them in a different
version a different person comes online
a different person shows up and and all
of us have that just as humans like you
know back in the day there was radio
voice and like ladies and gentlemen what
but like if I started doing that [__] to
you right now you'd be like what are you
like that's weird so there is a level of
like when you are aware that the cameras
on you have an image that is going to be
long lasting you have an awareness of it
but I think a lot of people think that
that's [__]
them I think so I love where you're
going with this I love where you're
going with this go ahead so how do we
realiz when we're fooling ourselves into
putting our energy into our image
instead of our image is an afterthought
of something people can judge us for
later if they want but we did the work
then they talk about who cares what the
image is it's an afterthought yeah so
Jake I I'm still on the same idea that
everything I don't know if I'm going to
explain this right but all the things
that are supposed to
happen Okay what I don't know how I've
been explaining this whole entire
Journey like it's the same thing right
the same Vibe or whatever when the
camera's on
you I like that I act like that all the
time why because what I want somebody to
see this that is how you can hold
accountability right
so check this out here's a metaphor I I
literally live my life in metaphor okay
because if I don't I I there is no anym
for me in this moment back up against
the wall I don't have that but I need
that for my for my male spirit I need
that right so imagine this imagine I'm a
guy it's an inspirational guy on
Instagram I go at 6: a.m. I go to the
track I take a little video of my feet
running and then I stop and get in the
car but there's a camera on
me okay if my heart is pure I don't need
the camera on me but if my heart is pure
I'm putting in that Mile right I'm not
doing that cool all right cool all right
cool let's get in the car
okay H use that thing that you just said
use that I I the other uh was like a
couple months ago um my son jet was and
and we're waffling with this right we're
the first generation that is of gentle
parenting of right this whole new idea
that people got going on and all this
kind of stuff we're waffling with ideas
from scripture
modern ways of parent we're we're
getting our footing right and um for the
first four years now we have not spanked
one of our children um I want to find a
different way to do it I'm also not
opposed to it at the same time why Jake
because when we go out as men and we do
dumb [__] we get smacked in the mouth
right let's be honest right um but I I
like um so where I'm getting at with
that is the other day my son was a
little rough with my daughter and I
grabbed him by the arm and I remember
grabbing him pretty hard and again
here's the accountability and here's the
Pure Heart most other people would have
been like totally justified not a big
deal bro like you didn't even hurt him
you just yanked him over but in that
moment I felt
anger that's not okay so if I had a
camera on me would I want somebody to
see
that no I wouldn't so that thing that
you just said can actually be used as a
beautiful thing to actually guide your
life and help
you is how would I want people to see me
how would I how would I want this story
to go how would I want this movie to
play out right I always say make the
decision that tells the best story right
so in this
moment this guy imagine you know we're
working in a movie right I said this in
my my speech a couple years ago you get
all the way up to the to the part where
it's like oh here we go is here's me
right is the guy going to quit the job
he hates it he's miserable dude we're
building a fantastic story here right
and then he quits his job and then he
Retreats and goes back do a different
job no one's reading that bro No One's
Gonna read that not only is no one gonna
read that or watch that I want to
inspire my son right I want him to be
like what did you do in this situation
my one of my biggest fears is saying I
don't know I don't know what you should
do
I don't know never been there never
tried that right again I feel like
and the only and everything in life is a
gamble bro right because if I go and do
all these things and exhaust myself in
every area to gain this wisdom and help
guide him we could argue that he does no
self-discovery and he could end up being
soft that is a risk but at the same time
if I do well enough he will also take
the the pattern of doing the same exact
thing for his own life then to pass it
on to his son right so that's that's
kind of where I'm at with it but with
this whole idea that you're talking
about
of how do we switch that I think you
literally using you set the stage for
like the camera's on you for a perfect
answer bro like the camera's on you how
do you want to be seen like think about
it we do so many things I always say
people got full closets and empty
fridges you care how you you care how
you seen but think about what's actually
most important you know you know what I
mean people got a closet for full of
Jordans and they have orange juice and
Rockstar in the fridge and that's it
yeah yeah it makes me think of those
videos sometimes I'll get fed videos of
um and I I've got to realize it's
because I'm spending time watching them
so they're feeding them to me but uh
like people going to get their nails
done and they're just like I don't got
any money though yeah literally like
what what are you doing at the nail
salon are you out of your [__] mind
but like in that moment you could hear
them like like the person doing their
nails records and you could hear that
person and hey for all I know it's
probably like a skit just to get could
be but um they're they're not taking
accountability they're like well so I
don't have the money what are you going
to do like there's just this constant
like not taking accountability for the
situation they're in and um I just think
like the more you bury yourself
underneath that the harder and harder it
is to to get out from underneath it dude
it's like stop putting your energy into
things that don't serve you like serving
the image of you is not the same thing
as serving you but um I do like what you
exactly that right there yeah run that
back like because that's exactly it and
also too I think again if you're not
awake you don't understand that that
story you just use is not a story about
finances it's not dud it's about what
they act that you take that show um
Atomic habits every action you take is a
vote for the person you want to be yeah
think that's extremely and again
correlate that to what we were just
talking about with the movie thing okay
what like if if if if this is a bottle
right if this is booze and I raise this
what action what does this say right
people are you're not we're not thinking
like that right if I
if I if I you know if I'm faithful but
I'm looking at girls on Instagram what
does that action say right this and
again it only happens with extreme
accountability that is the only thing
that's worked for me right I had a big
ego before I had my business but I had
no
business what am I doing wrong what am I
doing wrong I know I'm good at my skill
set but I have no business what am I
doing wrong but for the longest time it
wasn't my fault it was that they were
cheap or they couldn't afford me or they
didn't want to pay this or they didn't
want to pay that or they're stupid
because they don't want to use me they
want to use somebody
else guess who was losing the entire
time me I was the one losing they
weren't losing they were getting their
videos done those clients were getting
their videos done by somebody else so
that's the only thing that helped me
make progress was extreme accountability
so now I am overly accountable for
every situ even when things are good
right three and here's an extreme
situation three months ago I had the
biggest month I ever had in my life uh
financially and as sweet as it was I sat
down and I asked God if this is not the
motion that you intend for me to have
please remove it from my life and that
next month I lost both of my biggest
clients jez I don't have an I don't have
an issue with that why because I asked
for it right and I asked for it with
good intention Okay so
it's just so deep bro it's so deep and
and I I don't want to ramble and I don't
want to talk so much about myself but I
I think that the only way to truly go
hey you should try this is to say this
is where I was this is how I was feeling
this is kind of where I'm at now and
this was the the this bridged the Gap
you know what I mean so um I hope that
we did a good job of that I I really do
um but yeah I I don't know I mean yeah I
I think it comes through man I think um
I mean like you said before multiple
times um you know I'm not I'm not a
pastor I'm a stun writer you know I'm
I'm just a freaking DJ who enjoys
podcasting and I like poetry and stuff
and I I think about myself a lot and uh
I notice that that's selfish and so I
try to take okay I think about myself a
lot how can I take what I've learned
about myself my own life lessons and
repackage them in my rambling to other
people and maybe positively impact
someone else so I think be being upfront
with it and you know it's it's also
pretty easy like neither of us are
selling anything I don't have a sales
funnel for you to go down uh if I did
I'd tell you about it like link below
but I don't have one so yeah I think
that does come through man I think just
I I I contemplate the podcast space a
lot because I go through multiple months
sometimes where I'm like man podcast
like grown 30-year-old men podcasting is
somehow cringe as all heck sometimes and
then and and then I'll go through like
the next month and I'll be listening my
like listen to other people on podcast
and I'll be so freaking inspired and
they say the right thing at the right
time and I'm like oh yeah like yeah it
could be cheesy but it's good intention
and that comes through you know I mean
bro I I don't even look at it like that
I really look at it as just like two
dudes sitting down and having a
conversation and it I I think the only
time it's cringey bro I really do is
when there's no value I I really do and
that's why I tried my absolute best in
here and I hope anybody that listens to
it heard my heart that I try to lead
with value here because that's when it
is it's like when you're just talking
about very um surface level substance
type of things obviously if you're on a
financial podcast you're going to talk
about money right if you're on a sales
podcast you're going to talk about sales
but you're in the quote unquote mental
health space right so I feel like again
if we're just on here talking about our
problems with no solution or how do we
how do we not how do we work through
this or you know challenging some
narratives for people that open their
perspective I feel like you've done your
job and it's not um corny you know what
I mean I think you said that nicely I
think that's true I think um yeah and
that's what the podcast has turned into
me is I I show up and I I think if
you're just selling I think if you're
quote unquote selling air like we're
just talking nonsense yeah then yeah
you're probably on the path of like
being corny you know what I mean but I
don't think you do that bro yeah like I
don't have a I'm not fooled to think
that I'm like that interesting that I
can just go and ramble and it's actually
important like I you know I try to share
things that I'm learning about and try
to pull those out of other people that
are sitting across from me so I think he
did good man dude it was um was good to
catch up bro I think yeah no kidding bro
I have a lot to say bro I always have a
lot to say but yeah I'm never a man
short for Words bro I'm never a man
short for words well good thing because
uh I I work in the world of microphones
so you know we're talking it's it's good
to good to have a have such a a good
voice and a positive influence for
people and and be ble to kind of send
that megaphone out to people who will
listen and you know maybe they'll come
out a better version of themselves after
they listen to our rambling and
appreciate bro yeah I appreciate you
having me on bro yeah all right brother
well hey um uh all the love we'll be in
touch bro and uh listeners take care of
yourselves you know the deal have you
stretched today have you drank some
water y where's your gratitude uh Nate
got some physical activity yes please
for the love of gosh get your body
moving um I don't know if you got if you
got scripture or anything that you want
to leave us with but I have the
intuition to have you guide us out my
friend oh man okay
um wow bro um so geez this man put me on
um on the spot right here um I want to
talk to I feel like um kind of that
whole thing I just maybe round out a
little bit of what we talked about um
men have really been on my heart lately
lately because I feel like the world
asks so much of men right you need to be
this you need to be that you need to be
doing this not only is it asked it's
actually expected and if it's not
expected you know you're you're less
than right and I want to let every man
know especially my my guys that are
fathers going to be fathers husbands all
these things
that there is everyone's in a different
place in their Journey and when I say
that I mean that very very deeply as far
as even in their lineage right there is
problems that have been neglected by men
before you that need to be saw if you do
not solve them they will passed on and
passed on and passed on right
so sometimes other men have been put in
position for them to grab the lit torch
and run it straight into millions right
and then there's other guys that don't
even know where the torch is or the
torch is wet or there's no lighter and
they got and they're doing all these
things and they spend years and years
and years of this life trying to even
get the torch lit and then guess what
then they go and pass it on to their son
who then goes and runs it up right and
so if you are a man in this life if you
never make a million dollars if you
never dream that have that dream house
or that thing if the last thing that you
ever do and the only thing in this
physical life that you hang your hat on
is that you led your family down the
Narrow Path and that you were the first
people in your generation to break all
these things and go to the way the truth
and the light you have
succeeded and that's what I feel like
has been on my heart a lot is because
we're so worried about the external
things when not understanding that if we
neglect to even get the foundation built
nothing will stand after you go and
guess what then you have no control of
it once you're
gone Bravo man beautifully said thank
you for that appreciate it bro all right
Nate I'll talk to you soon man all the
love um yeah man I stop ring on just to
keep you on the hook it so great to talk
to you man I'll I'll be in touch peace
out everybody we learn how to have
better see you thanks guys at what age
should we learn to have better
conversations with
[Music]
ourselves knowledge is
power reality is
n
[Music]